じゃ 行ってくる
Well, I’ll be back.
覚 待ってよ！
Wait, Satoru!
大丈夫だって
Don’t worry.
こういうのは
少しでも早い方がいいんだから
The sooner I get back, the better.
でも…
But…
Don’t look at me like that.
そんな顔すんなって
俺が驚異的に言い訳うまいの
知ってるだろう？
You know that I’m unbelievably
good at making up excuses.
You’re a smooth talker, but…
口は うまいけどさ
Then it’s fine!
Satoru!
覚！
Saki?
早季？
私も行く 覚だけじゃ心配だし
I’m going too.
I’m worried when Satoru is alone.
富子さんなら
きっと分かってくれるから
I’m sure Tomiko-san will understand.
大丈夫だから
We’ll be fine.
やだなあ 覚と同じこと言ってる
Oh, gee.
Now I’m sounding like Satoru.
とにかく２人は ここで待ってて
Anyway, you two wait here.
早まったことしちゃ ダメだからね
Don’t be rash now.
Flakes
of
Snow
I’m sorry.
ごめんなさい
昨日はどうしても帰れなかったの
I just couldn’t come home yesterday.
おなか すいてない？
Are you hungry?
疲れていると思うけど
I know you must be tired, but the chairman of the Board of Education wants to see you.
教育委員長から
呼び出しが かかっている
今から 一緒に行こう
Let’s go there together now.
ちょっとだけ
休ませてやれないの？
Can we let her rest a little?
時間をあけるのは まずいよ
It’s not wise to make them wait.
大丈夫 お父さん 行こう
I’ll be fine.
Let’s go, Dad.
お待たせしました
Good day.
ここから先は お嬢さまだけ
I have been instructed to let only your daughter pass.
いらしていただきたい
とのことです
Saki, I don’t think I have to tell you,
早季 分かるわね
何でも尋ねられたことを
ありのままに答えるのよ
but please answer all questions as truthfully as you can.
分かってる
I know.
渡辺早季さんね
そこに おかけなさい
Watanabe Saki-san, yes?
Sit there.
私は副委員長の小松崎晶代です
I am the vice-chairman of the board, Komatsuzaki Masayo.
聞かれたことは 正直に答えなさい
Answer all questions truthfully.
Do not lie, and do not hide anything.
隠し事やウソをつかないように
分かりましたか？
はい
Do you understand?
Yes.
昨日の朝早く
伊東守君が家出をしたという
You learned that Itou Mamoru-kun ran away from home yesterday in the early hours of the morning.
報告がありました
間違いありませんか？
Is this correct?
間違いありません
Yes.
When did you learn about it?
あなたが そのことを知ったのは
いつですか？
登校する前です
Before school.
秋月真理亜さんが
知らせてくれました
Akizuki Maria-san told me.
それで あなたはどうしましたか？
What did you do after finding out?
とりあえず 学校に行って
We went to school at first, and later
looked for him when we had the chance.
それから
探しに行くことにしました
なぜ ご両親や担任に
報告しなかったのですか？
Why did you not inform your parents or your teacher?
できれば 大ごとなる前に
連れ戻したいと思ったからです
Because we hoped to bring him back before it became a bigger issue.
それは悪く言えば
隠蔽工作と同じです
You could construe that as an attempt to hide it from us.
その点について あなたは…
On those grounds, you…
分かりました
Very well.
質問を続けます
On to the next question.
あなたは 自由研究の時間に
伊東守君を探しに行きましたね
You went in search of Itou Mamoru-kun
during independent observation, I believe?
誰かと 一緒でしたか？
Who was with you?
秋月真理亜さんと 朝比奈覚君です
Akizuki Maria-san and Asahina Satoru-kun.
I see.
なるほど それで 伊東守君は
見つかったんですか？
Did you find Itou Mamoru-kun?
渡辺早季さん どうしたんですか？
What is it, Watanabe Saki-san?
これは正式の査問会です
This is an official court of inquiry!
あなたは真実を
述べなければならないんですよ！
You must speak truthfully!
朝比奈覚君は あなたたちが
Asahina Satoru-kun testified that you found Itou Mamoru-kun together,
伊東守君を発見したと
証言しています
足を痛めて動けなくなっていたと
the latter having injured his leg and unable to travel.
それで あなたと秋月真理亜さんが
介抱のために残り
He then left you and Akizuki Maria-san
behind to care for him, and returned alone.
彼 １人が
先に帰ったということでした
議長…
いいのよ
Chairman!
It’s fine.
ここは真実を知るために
設けられた場であって
This court was formed to establish the truth.
この子を わなにかけるのが
目的じゃないから
Trying to make her contradict herself is not the goal.
どうですか？
Now, then.
朝比奈君の言ったことは
全て事実ですか？
Did Asahina Satoru-kun tell us the truth?
はい
Yes.
Why did you return alone?
なぜ あなただけ戻ったのでしょう
We were expecting you to bring Itou Mamoru-kun with you.
私たちは あなたが
伊東守君を連れて帰還することを
期待していたのですが…
I urged Mamoru to come back with us.
私は 守に 一緒に帰るように
促しました
でも どうしても嫌だと言いました
But he refused no matter what I said.
帰ったら 僕は殺される！
They’ll kill me if I go back!
そうよ！ もう少しで
Exactly! He barely escaped death as it is!
守は 本当に
殺されるところだったんだから！
しかたなく 私１人で戻ったんです
There was nothing I could do, so I returned alone.
守を１人にできなかったので
真理亜が残りました
We didn’t dare leave Mamoru alone, so Maria stayed behind with him.
So we can assume that Akizuki Maria-san is still persuading him to return as we speak?
では 秋月真理亜さんは
引き続き 伊東守君の説得を
続けているんですね
はい
Yes.
自活するんだ
呪力があれば 何とかなるよ
I’ll live off the land.
I have my Cantus, so I’ll be fine.
僕は町で生きることを
許されないから しかたないけど
I have no choice because I can’t live in the villages anymore.
真理亜は そうじゃない
But that’s not true for you, Maria.
だから
私に ひと言も相談しないで
I guess that’s why you ran away
without asking me for advice, too.
１人で家出したのね
本当に 守みたいに優しいコは
どこにもいないわ
There really is nobody as kind as you.
でも これからは ずっと 一緒よ
But we’ll always be together from now on.
All right?
いいわね 約束よ
It’s a promise.
もう会えないの？
Will I ever see you again?
そんなことないわ
きっとまた会えるから
Of course.
I’m sure we’ll meet again.
真理亜…
Maria…
渡辺早季さん！
Watanabe Saki-san!
１人で帰ってきて
どうするつもりだったのですか？
What on Earth were you thinking when you returned alone?
分かりません
I don’t know.
あなた 一体…
What are you trying to…
もう迷うことは ないんですよ
There is no need for you to think so much.
ただ聞かれたことに 正直に答え
Simply answer our questions truthfully.
後の事は 私たちに任せなさい
Leave the rest to us.
いいですね？
分かりました
All right?
Yes.
伊東守くんは
帰るのが嫌だと言ったのですね
You said Itou Mamoru-kun was very reluctant to come home.
あなたは 当然
その理由を聞いてますね？
I assume you know the reason for this?
はい あっ…
Yes.
その理由とは何ですか？
What is it?
Answer the question!
さっさと答えなさい！
今 神栖66町が どういう状況に
あるか 分かっていますか？
Do you have any idea what’s happening
in the 66th district of Kamisu right now?
外出禁止令が敷かれ
住民は不安に おののいています
An order to remain indoors has been enacted and the people tremble with fear!
それも これも
たった１人の生徒の
And it can all be blamed on the
selfish actions of one single student!
自分勝手な行動が原因なんですよ
僕… 死にたくない！
I don’t want to die!
何とか言いなさい
Say something!
守が逃げ出したのは
I believe Mamoru ran because he didn’t want to die.
死にたくなかったからだと
思います
何を… おかしなことを言うのは
やめなさい
What? Don’t say something so absurd!
私は ただ…
質問に答えているだけです
I am only answering your question.
守は最近 ２度に渡って
不浄猫の接近を受けました
Mamoru was approached by a Tainted Cat on two separate occasions recently.
１度目は ただ 跡を
つけられただけだったようですが
The first time, it appeared to only tail him.
やめなさい あなたは 今
Stop!
Do you have any idea what you’re saying?!
とんでもないことを
言っているんですよ？
２度目は おとといの放課後
The second time was two days ago, after school.
Mamoru was ordered by our teacher to stay behind after school
守は担任から居残りを命じられ
しかも 中庭に近い場所へ
and sent to a room near the inner yard in a deliberate attempt to isolate him.
意図的に
１人で行くよう 仕向けられました
You…
あなた…
そこで 守は
Mamoru barely escaped death
when he met the Tainted Cat there.
もう少しで
不浄猫に殺されるところでした
だから 守は…
黙りなさい！
That is why Mamoru—
Silence!
あなたは
この査問会を侮辱しました
You have made a mockery of this hearing.
あなたの言動を
倫理規定に照らして
Your conduct constitutes a grave
violation under the Code of Ethics.
重大な罪を構成します
私も大変 残念です
I am very disappointed as well.
あなたのご両親も
このような結果になったことを
Your parents will surely lament that it has come to this.
さぞ悔やんでいることでしょう
私は処分されるんですか？
Will I be disposed of?
なんて おぞましい子なの
What a repulsive girl you are.
査問会の最中です 後にしなさい
The committee is in meeting.
Await your time.
Perhaps I came at a bad time.
お邪魔だったかしら
でも どうしても 今 お話しする
必要があったものだから
But I’m afraid I must speak here.
早季ちゃんのことは
私に任せてもらえないかしら
May I handle Saki-chan’s case?
Please pardon me, but the Board of Education has exclusive jurisdiction over such matters.
お言葉ですが
これは教育委員会の専管事項です
たとえ 富子様といえども
Outside interference would not be wise, Tomiko-sama, even if it is the request of one such as you.
このような形で干渉なさるのは
いかがなものかと…
そうね ごめんなさい
You’re right. My apologies.
でも 早季ちゃんのことについては
私にも責任があるの
However, I must partly take the blame for Saki-chan.
それは…
どういうことでしょうか？
I don’t quite understand.
私がね 早季ちゃんに
いろいろなことを教えたのよ
You see, I have told Saki-chan about many things.
不浄猫のことも その１つ
Including the Tainted Cats.
それは いささか
異例なことと思いますが…
That is quite unprecedented!
そうね
Yes.
But it was necessary to rear the person who may lead our villages in the future.
でも 将来の町の指導者を
養成するためには
必要なことだったわ
She will?
この子がですか？
So, Hiromi-chan…
だからね 宏美ちゃん
Please be lenient with Saki-chan.
早季ちゃんのことは
大目に見てあげて
富子様
今 現在 男の子だけではなく
Tomiko-sama…
The boy is not the only one missing.
女の子まで
行方不明になっているんです
A girl has disappeared as well!
I know that.
分かってるわ
でも こうなったのは
But is that not largely your own doing?
あなたたちの責任も
大きいんじゃないかしら
私どもの責任…？
Our doing?!
Yes.
そうよ そもそも
伊東守君の処分を決めたのは
The decision to dispose of Itou
Mamoru-kun was rash and unwise.
あまりに性急すぎた
それに その処分さえ
満足に果たせなかったからこそ
Your inability to successfully bring about his disposal…
こうした事態を招いたのでしょ
…was what caused this whole situation.
それは…
That…
もちろん 私自身にも責任はあるわ
I will not deny partial responsibility.
１班の子供たちに対する実験を
指示したのは 私だから
I’m the one who ordered for the experiment to be conducted on Group One, after all.
But now is not the time to dwell on the past.
でも今は そんな後ろ向きな議論を
しているときじゃないでしょ
これから どうするかを
１番に考えなくちゃ
We need to discuss how to proceed from here.
違うかしら
Am I wrong?
You are absolutely right.
おっしゃるとおりです
分かってもらえて うれしいわ
I’m happy we feel the same.
いろり端を貸してもらえるかしら
May I use your hearth?
あっ あの そちらは 今…
Um, right now, that room is…
いいのよ
全て そのままにしておいて
I don’t mind.
Don’t touch a thing in there.
召し上がれ
Eat.
Um, is Satoru all right?
あの… 覚は無事なんでしょうか
He’s fine. Don’t worry.
無事よ 心配いらないわ
Now eat while it’s still hot.
だから 冷めないうちに どうぞ
平気よ
Don’t worry.
命令しない限り 襲わないから
They only attack when commanded.
I see.
はい…
１つ お聞きしてもいいですか？
May I ask something?
どうぞ
Go ahead.
Tomiko-san—
富子さん… あっ あの 富子様は
I-I mean, Tomiko-sama…
ウフフ… 富子さんでいいわ
Tomiko-san is enough.
富子さんは さっき１班の子供に
Tomiko-san, you mentioned ordering for an experiment to be conducted on Group One.
実験を指示したって
おっしゃってましたよね？
まあ よく覚えてるのね
I see you were paying attention.
あなたたちは本当に特別だったの
You are all very special.
普通は 幼いころから何度も
反復される睡眠暗示をかけられて
Everyone is normally hypnotized repeatedly from a young age so we can control even their minds.
思考内容までが操作されているの
でも あなたたちから
思考の自由を奪うようなことは
However, we did not, by and large, take the
freedom of thought away from you and your friends.
ほとんど なかったのよ
どうして私たちだけが…
Why us?
それはね…
Because…
従順な子ヒツジだけでは
町は守れないから
Docile lambs alone cannot protect the villages.
指導者には 清濁 併せ飲む度量
Leaders need to be broad-minded and tolerant.
ときには 汚れ仕事も いとわない
強い信念が必要なの
Their convictions must be strong enough to do even dirty work from time to time.
でも 結果としては
However, too many unforeseen events have taken place.
こんなに次々と不測の事態が
起きてしまった
残念だったのは
My biggest regret is having to dispose of the boy we had the greatest hopes for.
町で 最も
将来を嘱望されていた子を…
今回のことでも
Regarding this case, normal children would be paralyzed with fear at the prospect of crossing the Holy Barrier.
普通の子なら
八丁標を越えるだけで
恐怖で足がすくむはずよ
でも あの子たちは違ったみたいね
They are different, however.
Threatened with death at home, they chose instead to live alone in the wilderness.
町に戻って
命を奪われるくらいならと
あえて 自活の道を選んだんでしょ
とても理性的な判断だったと
思うわ
A very rational decision, if you ask me.
それこそ
自由な思考の たまものだし
It is the result of free thinking.
私だって そうしたかもしれない
Perhaps I would’ve done the same.
However, it also threatens the
fundamental safety of the villages.
でも そのことが 今
町の安全を
根底から脅かしているの
２人がいなくなったことが
Is their departure really such a big problem to the villages?
町にとって そんなに
大きな問題なんでしょうか
I am quite sure they will never return.
２人とも
２度と町には戻らないと思います
I do not think they will have a negative influence.
悪い影響があるとは思えません
あなたには
You don’t see the true nature of the problem.
問題の本質が
全く見えていないのよ
What might that be?
どういうことですか…
知ってる？
Did you know?
Ancient civilization had something called nuclear weapons.
古代文明には
核兵器というものがあったの
たった１つで
都市を丸ごと壊滅させるだけの
Just one of them had the power to eradicate an entire city.
威力があったそうよ
だから
管理には神経をすり減らしたの
Managing them was the source of much deliberation and stress.
だけど もしかしたら
However, the situation we face now might be even worse.
現在の状況は
もっとひどいかもしれない
今の世界は 潜在的には
The world is now filled with something that is potentially far more fearsome.
それより はるかに恐ろしい存在で
満ちている
それは何ですか？
What is it?
人間よ
Humans.
たった１人の悪鬼によって
A single Fiend can effortlessly wipe out an entire district.
容易に１つの町が
皆殺しにされてしまうの
しかも 核爆弾とは違い
Moreover, unlike nuclear weapons, a Fiend slaughters for as long as his body permits.
体力さえ保てば 際限なく
殺戮を続けることだってありうる
でも きちんと予防すれば
But if we guard against that…
That’s not what I mean.
違う そうじゃないの
あなたは どういう形で
呪力が暴走するか
You’re too preoccupied with the processes by which Cantus can go out of control.
その様態だけに気をとられている
問題の本質は
そこに無限のエネルギーを
The real problem is that Cantus symbolizes endless energy.
秘めた力があるという事実
そのものなの
日本列島の人口は
今 ５万人～６万人
Between fifty to sixty thousand people now live on the Japanese archipelago.
それだけの数の脅威の可能性が
存在するということなの
Each one holds the potential to
bring about unimaginable horrors.
２人を連れ戻しなさい
Please bring them back.
If they come back, I will vouch for their safety.
町に帰って来さえすれば
２人の命は私が保証します
でも
このまま逃亡を続けるとしたら
But if they continue to hide from
the villages, they will not live long.
２人が長生きすることは
有り得ないのよ
Why?
どうしてですか！
The Board of Education will devote all their attention to their disposal.
教育委員会は ２人の処分に
全力をあげるでしょう
バケネズミのコロニーは 全て
All queerat colonies will be ordered to eliminate them.
２人を排除せよという指令を
受けとることになる
The neighboring districts will receive letters asking for help in their disposal.
近隣の町に
処分を依頼する文書が送られる
どの町も独自の方法を
持っているはずだから
They all have their own ways of dealing with the problem, which they will naturally use to defend themselves.
自衛のために それらを
行使することになるでしょう
そんな… ひどい
That’s so cruel.
Yes, so bring them both back before it happens.
だから
そうなる前に２人を連れ戻すのよ
３日 あげるわ
You have three days.
３日間なら
教育委員会を抑えておける
I’ll delay the Board of Education for three days.
I will leave immediately.
すぐ出発します
富子さんが来てくれなければ
I would have been prey for those cats had you not come, am I right?
私は この猫たちの
獲物になっていたんですね
それはどうかしら
I’m not too sure.
富子さんは…
Why do you hold so much influence?
どうして これほど強い影響力を
お持ちなんですか？
船着場まで送るわ
I’ll accompany you to the dock.
早季ちゃんは
権力の源泉って何だと思う？
Where do you think political power comes from?
The powerful men of old used fear through direct violence, wealth, brainwashing, and so forth to obtain power.
古代の権力者たちはね
直接的な暴力による恐怖や財力
洗脳による精神支配などの方法で
巧みに権力を手に入れてきたの
私には そのいずれもなかった
I didn’t use any of that.
唯一 恵まれていたのが…
All that I had on my side was…
時間なのよ
…time.
Time?
時間… ですか
そう 何の取り柄もない人間だけど
Yes.
I’m completely unremarkable as far as humans go, but I had a lot of time.
時間だけは たっぷりあったわ
早季ちゃんは 私が何歳に見える？
What age do I look like to you?
About 67.
67歳くらいですか？
今 かなり びっくりしたわ
That’s an amusing guess.
下の２つは当たってたから
You got the last two digits right.
私… 267歳なの
I’m 267 years old.
まさか
You can’t be…
私が悪鬼に遭遇したのは
My episode with the Fiend was 245 years ago.
今から245年前
倫理委員会 議長に就任したのは
I’ve been chairman of the Ethics Committee for 170 years.
170年前だったわ
どうして そんなに…
How did you…
長生きなのかって？
…live so long?
それとも
どうしてそんなに若いのかって
…remain so young?
思ってくれたのかしら
Is that what you’re thinking?
あらあら… そんなバケモノを
見るような目で見ないで
Please, don’t look at me like you’ve seen a ghost.
But…
そんな…
私は 本当に平凡な生徒だったの
I was a perfectly average student.
でも唯一 あの肆星にもできない
私だけの奥義
However, there is one thing I can do that even Shisei cannot.
それはね…
You see…
自分のテロメアを
修復できるっていうこと
I can regenerate my telomeres.
テロメア…？
Telomeres?
染色体の末端部分のことよ
That’s what we call the ends of our chromosomes.
Every time a cell divides, its telomeres are shortened a little because they can’t be fully replicated.
細胞が分裂するとき
末端まで複製が利かないので
テロメアは
少しずつ短くなっていくの
テロメアが すり減ってしまうと
Once the telomeres have worn down, the cells lose their ability to replicate,
細胞は
それ以上 分裂できなくなって
死を待つしかないの
and death is inevitable.
じゃあ テロメアを修復できれば
So you can live forever if you regenerate your telomeres?
永遠に生きられる
Who knows?
それは どうかしら
Nobody knows what forever is like.
誰も 永遠がどんなものか
知らないから
みんな いなくなって
私だけが残った
I live on while everyone around me passes away.
私と ここにある膨大な歴史が
I myself and the vast history contained up here is the source of my influence.
それが権力の源よ
いってらっしゃい 早季ちゃん
Have a safe journey, Saki-chan.
I will be back.
いってきます
I’ll have a new exercise for you once you return.
帰ってきたら 新しい課題を
やってもらうことになると思うわ
You must be quite bored with
what you’ve been doing in school.
今までのは
かなり退屈だったでしょう
そんなことは
Not at all.
つぼを直す技術だって
たまには役にたちますし
Learning how to fix a vase can be helpful.
I suppose.
そうね… これは内緒の話だけど
I’ll share a secret with you.
テロメアを
修復するためのイメージは
The mental image to repair your telomeres
is a little like the one needed to fix a broken vase.
割れたつぼを元通りにするのと
ちょっとだけ似てるのよ
Saki!
早季～！
覚！
Satoru?
よかった ここで追いつけて
I’m glad I caught up to you!
こんだけの雪の中
I was afraid I’d have to look all over for you in this snow.
野っ原を探すんじゃないかと
思ってたよ
Why? Weren’t you questioned by the Board of Education?
何で？ 教育委員会で
査問を受けたんでしょう？
受けたよ
その後 ずっと待たされてさ
Yeah.
They made me wait for ages afterwards.
そしたら 今度は
Then they suddenly told me to catch up to you.
すぐに 早季を追いかけろって
言われて
もう早季が戻って来たなんて
知らないから
I was really confused because I had no idea you came back.
訳 分かんなくて びっくりしたよ
It really surprised me.
状況は分かってる？
Do you know what we need to do?
ああ
真理亜と守を連れ帰るんだろ
Yeah.
We need to bring Maria and Mamoru back, right?
行こう
Let’s go.
あれ？
Huh?
うっ… もう 急に止まんないでよ
Hey, don’t just stop.
この辺だったよな…
Wasn’t it around here?
あの松…
That pine…
The igloo…
かまくらは…
さよなら
Goodbye.
Nakisou na aoringo kakaeteru mune no oku
泣きそうな青リンゴ  抱えてる胸の奥
In my chest, I carry a green apple that wets my eyes
Korogatte tsuyogatte
転がって  強がって
I fall over yet pretend to be strong
Kyuukutsu na sora niramu
窮屈な空睨む
I glower at the sky and it seems to suffocate me
Unmei ni juujun ni
運命に従順に
Do I look like I'd wait quietly
Jukusu no wo matsu mon ka
熟すのを待つもんか
For destiny to ripen it?
Sen no kaze
千の風
The winds
Agaite sakende
あがいて  叫んで
I struggle and scream
Fuke fuke
吹け吹け
Blow and blow
Watashi wa shabondama
わたしはしゃぼん玉
I'm a soap bubble
Soredemo shinjiteru
それでも信じてる
And still I have faith
Yokisenu arashi ni
予期せぬ  嵐に
In a sudden storm
Joushou shite kakou shite
上昇して  下降して
I rise and fall
Aragau shabondama
あらがうしゃぼん玉
I fight, soap bubble that I am
Soredemo ikiteku
それでも生きてく
And still I live on
Hajikeru shunkan niji hanate
弾ける瞬間  虹、放て
I make a rainbow when I burst
お久しぶりでございます 神様
FROM
THE
NEW
WORLD
It has been a long time, gods.
君の力を借りたい
We need your help.
As you wish.
かしこまりました
Don’t look back.
振り返らないで
アイツら ひょっとしたら…
I get the feeling they’re trying to replace us humans.
人間に取って代わろうと
してるんじゃないかって気がする
What?